so this is the solution for our arabe
timing quiz the first part we were asked
when does this multiplication
instruction issue execute right and
commit this instruction will issue in
the second cycle the reason for that is
that we have still to multiply divide
reservation stations this is using the
first one we can use the second one here
so we can actually issue in the second
cycle so the correct answer here is 2
for issue for execution we are using r5
and r6 that doesn't depend on r2 so we
can actually begin execution right after
the issue in cycle 3 the multiplication
will take two cycles to execute so it's
executing in cycles three and four it's
going to try to write the result in
cycle five and now when does it commit
it commits when it has both written the
result
and when all previous instructions have
committed the previous instruction
commit is happening later so we will
commit in cycle eight right after the
first instruction has committed